<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Konstellation – KRE</title><link>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/</link><description>Recent content in KRE on Konstellation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Concepts</title><link>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/concepts/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-kre">What is KRE?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is an engine capable of deploy, manage and monitor a full AI solution in production in seconds using &lt;a href="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/website/docs/krt/">KRT files&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KRE has the following main concepts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#engine">Engine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#runtimes">Runtimes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#versions">Versions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#workflow">Workflows&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="engine">Engine&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Engine component is the central component that works as the &lt;strong>operation tool&lt;/strong> to create, manage and monitor all the resources associated with each solution that you would put in production. It includes an admin web app, an API and some other components.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4" style="max-width: 1010px">
&lt;img class="card-img-top" src="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/website/docs/kre/concepts/kre_overview_hu7a5b5d5cc96d9ada230aeb87ed5b9159_76309_1000x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="1000" height="347">
&lt;div class="card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0">
&lt;p class="card-text">
Engine components are deployed in a specific k8s namespace. The runtimes are deployed in other namespaces.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Using the admin web app you will able to manage users, permissions and runtimes. You can see the &lt;a href="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/website/docs/kre/tasks/">tasks&lt;/a> if you want more information about what things you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="runtimes">Runtimes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Inside a KRE you can create as many runtimes as you need. A runtime is identified by a name and a description and it is where you can upload one or more solutions that we call versions. For example, you can deploy a KRE for the ClientX and create a runtime for each ClientX project. Inside each ClientX project you will upload the versions of your AI solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going into greater detail, a runtime is an environment that is &lt;strong>isolated&lt;/strong> from all other runtimes and other resources. Inside a runtime we will find the resources associated to your solution versions, a messaging system used to dispatch messages between components, databases to store metrics or generic data, a s3 store and internal components like an API to process incoming messages received from the KRE admin.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4" style="max-width: 710px">
&lt;img class="card-img-top" src="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/website/docs/kre/concepts/runtime_overview_hu7a5b5d5cc96d9ada230aeb87ed5b9159_96017_700x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="700" height="522">
&lt;div class="card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0">
&lt;p class="card-text">
All versions share databases, storage and message system but it is isolated from other runtimes.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="versions">Versions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A version is a collection of all things needed for your AI solution to work like code, models, assets,&amp;hellip; This is a key concept in KRE because if you make changes at any level, model or code, you then have a new version that must be uploaded. This make versions immutable entities easier to track and debug over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To upload your versions into a runtime you will need a KRT file. To learn how to create a &lt;a href="https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/website/docs/krt/">KRT file&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="workflows">Workflows&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>Docs: Installation</title><link>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/installation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>KRE is ready to be deployed in a Kubernetes cluster or single node. This section contains guidelines for common scenarios for setup, deployment, cluster preparation and Helm values configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Tasks</title><link>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://konstellation-io.github.io/website/docs/kre/tasks/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>